Guide to the Transport Workers Union of America Records WAG.235
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series VII: Unprocessed Material: Railroad Division Records, General Files, and Ledgers, 1935-1990
  - Michael J. Quill: Air Transport Division - Local 550 ALSSA: Financial, 1961-1963 (Box 129, Folder 4)
  - Michael J. Quill: Air Transport Division - Local 550 ALSSA Negotiations Proposals, Oct 9, 1961 (Box 129, Folder 5)
  - Michael J. Quill: Air Transport Division - Local 550 ALSSA: Executive Board Meetings, Jun. - Nov. 1962 (Box 129, Folder 6)
  - M. J. Quill: Air Transport Division - Local 550 ALSSA Conventions, Apr. 19-20, 1963 (Box 129, Folder 7)
  - Michael J. Quill: Air Transport Division - Local 550 - ALSSA: Constitution and By-Laws, Undated (Box 129, Folder 8)
  - M. J. Quill: Air Transport Division - Local 550 - ALSSA: Transcript - ALSSA Convention, Undated [1961] (Box 129, Folder 9)
  - Executive Board: Air Transport Division - Organization of Flight Attendants, Jan. - Feb. 1962 (Box 129, Folder 10)
  - Pan Am. Union Committee Meetings, Apr. - May 1971 (Box 129, Folder 11)
  - Industrial Union Committee Correspondence, 1955-1956 (Box 129, Folder 12)
  - Seaboard Coal Dock; Penn Central Railroad; Lehigh Valley Railroad; Hoboken Shop; Erie Lakawanna; Baltimore & Ohio Railroad, 1969-1970 (Box 129, Folder 13)
  - TWU Cope Contributions, 1955-1956 (Box 129, Folder 14)
  - Transit Locals, 1956-1957 (Box 129, Folder 15)
  - TWU Correspondence, 1952-1956 (Box 129, Folder 16)
  - Puerto Rico and Correspondence, 1952-1959 (Box 129, Folder 17)
  - Airline Mergers, Feb. 25 - Jun. 21, 1963 (Box 129, Folder 18)
  - Airline Publicity and General Correspondence, 1963 (Box 129, Folder 19)
  - PRR Contracts and Agreements, 1964-1971 (Box 130, Folder 1)
  - Railroad Brotherhood, 1964-1965 (Box 130, Folder 2)
  - Merging of TWU and Railroad Locals, Feb. 25, 1964 - Jun. 18, 1964 (Box 130, Folder 3)
  - Railroad Correspondence, 1965 (Box 130, Folder 4)
  - Pennsylvania Railroad, 1964 (Box 130, Folder 5)
  - RR Division Materials: Presidents Council, Correspondence, Maps, Newspaper Clippings, 1959-1969 (Box 130, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Sept 5 - 13, 1960 (Box 130, Folder 7)
  - Shirley - Phila. PRR Strike, 1960 (Box 130, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, Oct. - Nov. 1960 (Box 130, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence to TWU Locals, Aug - Sept 1960 (Box 130, Folder 10)
  - RRD Reports, 1970 (Box 130, Folder 11)
  - RRD Correspondence, Press Releases, Newspaper Clippings re: Penn Central Strike, 1969-1970 (Box 130, Folder 12)
  - RRD Insurance, Negotiations, DLMs, PRR Vote on Agreement, and RRD Organizing, 1969 (Box 130, Folder 13)
  - Railroad Division: Correspondence, Publicity, Negotiations, Membership, Penn Central Bankruptcy & S.B.A. Dockets # 1 - 55, 1940-1971 (Box 131)
  - Cash Receipt Ledgers, Sept 1, 1944 - Nov 1949 (Box 132)
  - Cash Receipt Ledgers, Jul 1951 - May 1955 (Box 133)
  - Cash Receipt Ledgers, Jan 1935 - Apr 1937 (Box 134)
  - Cash Receipt Ledgers, Jan 1, 1944 - Jul 31, 1946 & Aug 1, 1946 - Jan 31, 1948 (Box 135)
  - Cash Receipt Ledgers, Feb 1, 1952 - Dec 7, 1954 & Dec 13, 1954 - May 16, 1955 (Box 136)
- Series VIII: Photographs, Glass Negatives, and Slides
  - Transport Workers Union of America (general and unidentified), 1940-1967, undated (Box 146, Folder 1)
  - Transport Workers Union of America (general and unidentified), undated (Box 146, Folder 2)
  - Air Transport Division, 1977 (Box 146, Folder 3)
  - Air Transport Division: House Subcommittee on Aviation Safety, 1976 (Box 146, Folder 4)
  - Air Transport Division: Local 500 (Miami, FL), 1949 (Box 146, Folder 5)
  - Air Transport Division: Local 501, 1965 (Box 146, Folder 6)
  - Air Transport Division: Local 550 (Air Line Stewards and Stewardesses Association) (ALSSA) I, 1961-1971, undated (Box 146, Folder 7)
  - Air Transport Division: Local 550 (Air Line Stewards and Stewardesses Association) (ALSSA) II, 1961-1971, undated (Box 146, Folder 8)
  - Air Transport Division: Local 550 (Air Line Stewards and Stewardesses Association) (ALSSA) III, 1961-1971, undated (Box 146, Folder 9)
  - Air Transport Division: Local 550 (Air Line Stewards and Stewardesses Association) (ALSSA) IV, 1961-1971, undated (Box 146, Folder 10)
  - Air Transport Division: Local 550 (Air Line Stewards and Stewardesses Association) (ALSSA): American Airlines Delegation to Albany, NY, 1968 (Box 146, Folder 11)
  - Air Transport Division: Local 550 (Air Line Stewards and Stewardesses Association) (ALSSA): American Airlines Negotiations, 1975-1976 (Box 146, Folder 12)
  - Air Transport Division: Local 550 (Air Line Stewards and Stewardesses Association) (ALSSA): American Airlines Picket Line/Protest, 1968 (Box 146, Folder 13)
  - Air Transport Division: Local 550 (Air Line Stewards and Stewardesses Association) (ALSSA): American Airlines Picket Line/Protest (negative), 1968 (Box 146, Folder 14)
  - Air Transport Division: Local 550 (Air Line Stewards and Stewardesses Association) (ALSSA): Contract Signings, 1967-1968 (Box 146, Folder 15)
  - Air Transport Division: Local 550 (Air Line Stewards and Stewardesses Association) (ALSSA): Department of Labor Hearings (Washington DC), 1967 (Box 146, Folder 16)
  - Air Transport Division: Local 550 (Air Line Stewards and Stewardesses Association) (ALSSA): Equal Employment Opportunity Hearing (includes photo of Betty Friedan), 1967 (Box 146, Folder 17)
  - Air Transport Division: Local 550 (Air Line Stewards and Stewardesses Association) (ALSSA): International Executive Council Meeting, 1963 (Box 146, Folder 18)
  - Air Transport Division: Local 550 (Air Line Stewards and Stewardesses Association) (ALSSA): New York State Commission on Human Rights Hearings on American Airlines, 1966-1967 (Box 146, Folder 19)
  - Air Transport Division: Local 550 (Air Line Stewards and Stewardesses Association) (ALSSA): Northwest Airlines Picket Line, 1967 (Box 146, Folder 20)
  - Air Transport Division: Local 550 (Air Line Stewards and Stewardesses Association) (ALSSA): TWA Demonstration, 1962, 1970 (Box 146, Folder 21)
  - Air Transport Division: Local 550 (Air Line Stewards and Stewardesses Association) (ALSSA): TWA Flight Attendants Strike, Negotiations, Settlement I, 1973 (Box 146, Folder 22)
  - Air Transport Division: Local 550 (Air Line Stewards and Stewardesses Association) (ALSSA): TWA Flight Attendants Strike, Negotiations, and Settlement II, 1973 (Box 147, Folder 1)
  - Air Transport Division: Local 551, 1974-1977 (Box 147, Folder 2)
  - Air Transport Division: Local 552, 1974-1977 (Box 147, Folder 3)
  - Air Transport Division: Local 552: Bumper Sticker, undated (Box 147, Folder 4)
  - Anniversaries (20th), 1954 (Box 147, Folder 5)
  - Faber, Gustav, undated (Box 147, Folder 6)
  - Faber, Gustav: Los Angeles Organizing Drive, 1952 (Box 147, Folder 7)
  - Faber, Gustav: United Railroad Workers, 1951-1952 (Box 147, Folder 8)
  - Local 1 (Akron, OH), 1943, 1946 (Box 147, Folder 9)
  - Local 100 (New York, NY), 1937-1938 (Box 147, Folder 10)
  - Local 100 (New York, NY), 1949 (Box 147, Folder 11)
  - Local 100 (New York, NY), Aug 24, 1954 (Box 147, Folder 12)
  - Local 100 (New York, NY), Jun 23, 1962 (Box 147, Folder 13)
  - Local 100 (New York, NY), undated (Box 147, Folder 14)
  - Local 100 (New York, NY): Cartoon, undated (Box 147, Folder 15)
  - Local 100 (New York, NY): Picket Line, 1941 (Box 147, Folder 16)
  - Local 101 (Brooklyn, NY): Counting Ballots for Mail Referendum Election of Officers, 1953-1954 (Box 147, Folder 17)
  - Local 161 (Philadelphia, PA), undated (Box 147, Folder 18)
  - Local 175 (Baltimore, MD), undated (Box 147, Folder 19)
  - Local 206 (New Orleans, LA), circa 1947-1949 (Box 147, Folder 20)
  - Local 214 (Pikesville, KY), 1946 (Box 147, Folder 21)
  - Local 220 (Fairfield, AL): Strike, 1941 (Box 147, Folder 22)
  - Local 223/228 (Omaha, NE): Officers, 1955 (Box 147, Folder 23)
  - Local 234, 1944, 1954 (Box 147, Folder 24)
  - Local 234 (Philadelphia, PA), 1958 (Box 147, Folder 25)
  - Local 241: Columbia University Strike, 1946 (Box 147, Folder 26)
  - Local 260 (Houston, TX): President Quill's Visit, circa 1953 (Box 147, Folder 27)
  - Local 270: Long Island Railroad Organizing Drive, 1948 (Box 147, Folder 28)
  - Local 292, 1975 (Box 147, Folder 29)
  - Local 600: Puerto Rico, 1952 (Box 147, Folder 30)
  - Local 700 (includes correspondence), 1957 (Box 147, Folder 31)
  - Local 2001: Pennsylvania Railroad Strike, 1960 (Box 147, Folder 32)
  - New York State CIO Annual Convention (16th), undated (Box 147, Folder 33)
  - Northwest Airlines Negotiations, 1974 (Box 147, Folder 34)
  - O'Reilly, Gerald, 1943, 1947 (Box 147, Folder 35)
  - Parade (unidentified), circa 19601-1964 (Box 147, Folder 36)
  - Poor People's March (Washington, DC), Jun 19, 1968 (Box 147, Folder 37)
  - Quill, Michael J., 1937-1959, undated (Box 147, Folder 38)
    Includes an image from the Transport Workers Union Local 100's 1937 BMT "powerhouse" strike, 1943 snapshots of friends and/or TWU members in the United States armed forces, and a lively personal photograph of Mike Quill with a group of young people ca. 1928/1929.
  - Quill, Michael J.: Campaign, 1944, 1947 (Box 147, Folder 39)
  - Quill, Michael J.: Portraits of Correspondents, 1943 (Box 147, Folder 40)
  - Quill, Shirley, undated (Box 147, Folder 41)
  - Railroad Division: Strike, 1960 (Box 147, Folder 42)
  - Sports Department, undated (Box 147, Folder 43)
  - Subway Car (negative), undated (Box 147, Folder 44)
  - Tamiment Library Event, 1987 (Box 147, Folder 45)
  - Glass Negatives, Undated (Box 147, Folder 46)
  - Michael Quill on Television, Circa 1965 (Box 147, Folder 47)
  - Glass Negatives: Presentation, Undated (Box 148, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook: Michael Quill Visit to Israel, 1953 (Box 148, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook: Michael Quill Visit to Israel, 1953 (Box 148, Folder 3)
- Series IX: Archived Website, Sep 25, 2007-ongoing
  The Transport Workers Union of America (TWU) is a labor union that was founded in 1934 by subway workers in New York City. The TWU has four divisions: Railroad; Gaming; Airline; Transit; and Utility, University and Service. The Union has 114 autonomous locals representing over 200,000 members and retirees in 22 states around the country. The TWU is a member of the AFL-CIO and the International Transport Workers Federation (ITF). The website includes a blog, blogs related to different industries within the union, their political action committee, Committee On Political Education (COPE), their publications, TWU Express and ATD Insider, reports, conference materials, and images.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
- Series X: Other formats: artwork, certificates, clippings, audiovisual materials, 1930-2001
  Scope and Contents
  Series X consists of materials separated from the original collection accession or included in Accessions NPA 1999.026 and 2017.078. Items include original artwork and cartoons, ephemera, certificates, maps, clippings, exhibit materials, films reels, VHS tapes, and compact discs.
  - Artifacts, ephemera, 1930-1963 (Box 149, Folder 1-21)
  - Other formats (Box 150, Folder 1-5)
  - Other formats (Box 151, Folder 1-7)
  - Audiovisual materials (Box 152)
  - Oversize Unprocessed (Folder 1)